Always make a scene.
Babylon is a drama, comedy film directed by Damien Chazelle.
A tale of outsized ambition and outrageous excess, tracing the rise and fall of multiple characters in an era of unbridled
decadence and depravity during Hollywood's transition from silent films to sound films in the late 1920s.
Manny Torres, played by Diego Calva.
Nellie LaRoy, played by Margot Robbie.
Jack Conrad, played by Brad Pitt.
Sidney Palmer, played by Jovan Adepo.
Elinor St. John, played by Jean Smart.
Truck Driver, played by J.C. Currais.
Babylon is a 2022 American epic period black comedy drama
film written and directed by Damien Chazelle.
It features an ensemble cast that includes Brad Pitt, Margot Robbie,
Diego Calva, Jean Smart, Jovan Adepo and Li Jun Li.
It chronicles the rise and fall of many characters during Hollywood's
change from silent to sound films in the late 1920s.
Chazelle began developing Babylon in July 2019, with Lionsgate
Films as the frontrunner to acquire the project.
It was announced that Paramount Pictures had acquired
worldwide rights in November 2019.
Much of the main cast joined the project between January 2020 and August 2021,
and filming took place in Los Angeles from July to October 2021.
Babylon premiered at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Los Angeles on November 14,
2022, and was released in the United States on December 23, 2022.
It was met with a polarized response from critics upon release and was a box-office bomb, grossing $63
million against a production budget of $78–80 million and losing Paramount $87 million.
It received five nominations at the 80th Golden Globe Awards (including Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy, winning Best Original Score), three
nominations at the 76th British Academy Film Awards (winning Best Production Design) and three nominations at the 95th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of elephant, gambling,
gambling debt, movie business, orgy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.